# **Danny Yu | Software Engineer**

Former insurance underwriter turned Software Engineer, with experience in developing rapport, explaining terminology, and highlighting the unique benefits of the many products the company offers. Coordinated with multiple teams within the company to deliver a complete product in a timely manner to satisfy everyone and most importantly the client. As a Software Engineer, these tools will help benefit the company and its end-users.

## **SKILLS**

- Languages: JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Python, SQL, Mongo, JSON, Typescript, EJS, DTL
- Databases: PostgreSQL, MongoDB | Other: RESTful Routing, JSON API
- Libraries/Frameworks: React, Express.js, Django, Jquery, Bootstrap, Flask

## **SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS**

 $\textbf{SpaceCommerce} \mid [\underline{GitHub}] \mid [\underline{Deployed}] \parallel MongoDB, Express, React, Node, Axios,$ 

(11/2022 - 11/2022)

E-Commerce Website for Celestial Objects

- Utilized a MERN stack (MongoDB, Express, React.js, Node.js) to build a full-stack application in 5 days. With full create, read, update, delete (CRUD) operations hitting all golden 7 RESTful API calls.
- The backend database is deployed with Railway and Atlas MongoDB. Tested API routes using Postman to ensure functionality during production.
- Built with User Authentication using JWT Tokens and passwords are hashed with Bcrypt.
- Implemented a Centralized Workflow Git control with a team of 5 during the production of the application with frequent commits until deployment.

Better Reddit | [GitHub] | [Deployed] | React, Axios, Django, PostgreSQL

(11/2022 - 11/2022)

We recreated Reddit, but butter with bread.

- Built a full stack social media application in 7 days, with full create, read, update, and delete (CRUD) operations
  using React, Django, and Postgresql.
- Implemented user authentication with JWT tokens, Django, and Cors. Passwords are hashed with Argon2ID(winner of the 2015 Password Hashing Competition) to ensure security.
- Developed advanced features such as a dynamic search bar, Live Chat, custom profiles, dark mode, and more.
- Practiced a Feature Branch Workflow with a team of 10 during production to streamline new features and minimize merge conflicts with over 600 commits.

Rick and Morty Frontend Project | [GitHub] | [Deployed] | React

(10/2022 - 10/2022)

Rick and Morty API with characters, episodes, and location info

- implemented Axios to perform get() request to the Rick and Morty API
- Created an application with a mobile-first approach and styled using the Style-Components module for React.
- Created a dynamic search bar component that can filter through 3 different endpoints.

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Commercial Line Underwriter | USI | Staten Island, NY/Remote

(07/2019 - 07/2022)

- Managed an extensive list of over 20 different types of clients from daycares to manufacturers
- Analyzed over 15+ carriers to maximize coverage for the client and profit for the companies.
- Collaborated with internal teams to cross-sell multiple products to maximize profit and coverage for the client.

Commercial Line Underwriter | Regency Insurance Brokerage Services | Staten Island, NY (07/201

(07/2015 - 07/2019)

- Generated \$200,000+ monthly bound new business premium with an amazing profit-to-loss ratio
- Created manuals, documents, and procedures to streamline training new hires and quoting accounts.
- Trained over 5+ assistants on company procedures and carrier guidelines.
- Refined the team's monthly data and marketing pamphlets for presentations, meetings, and conventions.
- Organized and closed over 100+ outstanding inspection reports.

### **EDUCATION**

General Assembly, Software Engineering Immersive | New York, NY John Jay of Criminal Justice College, B.S. | New York, NY

(09/2022 - 12/2022)